(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T22:22:16.259888",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
わためのうた3D 始まりよーん！
Watame's Song 3D is starting!
せーのっ
One, two!
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's a no-no,
もう そんなんじゃほら
See, that's already
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Getting our hearts moving on, further and further.
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words can destroy our relationship,
言葉を消せばいいやって
I thought, "Let's just get rid of words,"
思ってた 恐れてた
I was so scared.
だけど あれ? なんか違うかも
But wait... maybe that's wrong?
千里の道も一歩から
Every journey begins with a single step,
石のようにかたい そんな意志で
With a will as hard as stone!
ちりも積もればやまとなでしこ?
Will dust pile up into a Yamato Nadeshiko?
しー抜きで
Without the "shi"?
いや 死ぬ気で!
No, with a will to die!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffily, fluffily,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ
When you call my name,
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Just that lifts me up into the sky.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluffily, fluffily,
あなたが笑っている
When you smile,
それだけで笑顔になる
Just that makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう
Dear God, thank you.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just fate's playful prank,
巡り逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm so happy that we were able to meet.
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's a no-no,
もう そんなんじゃほら
See, that's already
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Getting our hearts moving on, further and further.
そう そんなんじゃやだ
Yup, that's a no-go,
ねえ そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's a bit too early,
私のこと 見ててね ずっとずっと
Don't take your eyes off me, never and ever.
私の中のあなたほど
The more of you in me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
And that my existence in you,
まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
I know I'm not as big as you, but I know
今この同じ瞬間共有してる実感
That in this same moment we share this feeling.
ちりも積もればやまとなでしこ?
If all dust settles, a Yamato Nadeshiko?
略して? ちりつもやまとなでしこ!
For short? Dust settles into a Yamato Nadeshiko!
逆して? ちりつもやまとなでこ!
Reversed? Dust settles into Yamato Nadeko!
くらくらり くらくラル
Swooningly, swoonity,
あなたを見上げたら
When I look at you,
それだけで眩しすぎて
Just that makes me daze to your radiance.
くらくラル くらくらり
Swoonity, swooningly,
あなたを想っている
When I think of you,
それだけでとけてしまう
Just that makes me melt to the ground.
神様ありがとう
Dear God, thank you.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if it's just fate's playful prank,
巡り逢えたことが 幸せなの
I'm so happy that we were able to meet.
そう そんなんじゃやだね
Yup, that's a no-go,
そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's a bit too early,
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Don't take your eyes off me, never and ever.
せーのっ
One, two!
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's a no-no,
もうそんなんじゃほら
See, that's already
こころはしんかするよ もーっともーっと
Making our hearts evolve more and more.
ことばにすればきえちゃうかんけいなら
If our bond would vanish into words,
ことばをきせばいいやって
Better not say anything, 'cause...
おもってた？ おそれてた？
Did you think so? Were you scared?
だけど あれっ？ なんかちがうかも
But wait? Maybe something's off.
せんりのみちもいっぽから！
Every journey begins with a step!
「し」ぬきで いや しぬきで！
Without "shi"—no, with all my might!
ふわふわり ふわふわぬ
Fluffily, fluffily,
あなたがなまえをよぶ
When you call my name,
それだけで ちゅうえうかぶ
Just that makes me float up in the air.
ふわふわぬ ふわふわり
Fluffily, fluffily,
あなたがわらっている
When you show your smile,
それだけで えがおになる
Just that brings a smile to my face.
かみさま ありがとう
Dear God, thank you,
うんめいのいたずらでも
Even if it's destiny's prank,
めぐりあえたことが
I'm so happy that
しあわせなの
We were able to meet.
でもそんなんじゃだめ もうそんなんじゃほら
But that's a no-no, see, that's already
こころはしんかするよ もっともっと
Making our hearts evolve more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ ねえそんなんじゃまだ
Yup, that's a no-go, hey, that's still too early,
わためのことみててね ずっとずっと
Please keep watching Watame, always and forever.
曇天羊
[Title: Donten Hitsuji]
たとえばよく晴れた曇り空
For instance, under a brightly cleared cloudy sky,
キャンバスに見立てて今僕は
Setting it as a canvas, right now I
何を描こう
What should I paint?
おろしたての靴で走り出す
Running out in freshly unboxed shoes,
道とも呼べぬ獣道
On a beast trail that can't even be called a path.
汚れてしまうことを恐れてちゃ
If you're afraid of getting dirty,
どこにも行けないんだって、ねえ？
You can't go anywhere, right?
よくない天気に顔伏せ歩いて
Walking with my head down in bad weather,
すべて見落すくらいならいっそ夢物語で良いから
If I'm going to miss everything, I'd rather it be a fairy tale.
can you see, cloudy sheep?
たとえばよく晴れた曇り空
For instance, under a brightly cleared cloudy sky,
キャンバスに見立てて思い描いた 君の笑顔
Painting your smile on the canvas in my mind,
今は辛くても むしゃらに叫んだ日々が
Even if it's hard right now, the days I cried out recklessly
雲を破り裂いて 一筋の光、差し込んできて
Tear through the clouds, letting a single beam of light shine through,
青空の下で また君と出会いたい
Wanting to meet you again under the blue sky.
タピオカミルクって勢いよく飲みますと、
When you drink tapioca milk too fast,
喉にタピオカがパーンって入ってきて、
a pearl shoots straight down your throat with a "bam,"
ある、いま、あれ人殺せる、平気だと今日思ったんすよねー。
and I thought today, "Man, that could totally kill someone."
看板どうどう！どどど！つのまきわためです！
Our sign is proud! Do-do-do! I'm Tsunomaki Watame!
今日は3Dお披露目に来てくれて、ありがとうー！
Thank you so much for coming to my 3D debut today!
いつもこの牧場で歌を歌ったりしたりしてさ、
Usually, I sing songs here on this ranch,
どう？どう？どう？
How is it? How is it? How is it?
かめだみてんで
Looking at turtles...
わためは…どう？
Watame is... how?
か、かわいいですか？
A-are I cute?
それはそうと、置いておいて、
Anyway, setting that aside,
今日はなんかみんなが来てくれてるみたいなんだけど、
it seems like everyone came to see me today—
羊のみんな、わためと、あい…だ…！
sheep everyone, with Watame, me, e... t...!
早く動かして貰って
I had it made to move quickly,
よいしょ
There we go.
あいだ！
Ah!
いっぱい来たなー！
So many came!
はげたんのいっぱい来たなー！
So many baldy ones came!
たくさん来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming!
これ、わたメイトも3Dになっちゃったね。
And look, Watamates became 3D too.
これ、実は、あの、お尻からも見れるし、横からも見れるし、これ3Dになっちゃったんだよね、わたメイトと一緒に。
You can actually see it from behind, and from the side too... They've become 3D along with Watamate!
デビューしちゃったね、わたメイトも。
They debuted in 3D too, Watamate!
3Dデビューおめでとう！
Congratulations on your 3D debut!
そして今日はここに、#角巻わため3D このハッシュタグをぜひ使って、もろて、ツイートとか、あとスクショも、あの、いっぱい撮って、
And today, please use the hashtag `#TsunomakiWatame3D` right here, take lots of tweets and screenshots,
もらって、大丈夫なので、本当たくさんツイートしてください！
and it's totally fine, so please tweet a lot!
ナンバーワン取ろうぜ。
Let's take number one!
トレンドナンバーワン取ろうぜ。
Let's take number one on trending.
では、ちょっとコメントを読みながら、ちょっと感想とか聞いたりしてみたいなと思うんだけど、
Well, I thought I'd read some comments and hear your impressions and thoughts,
わための歌の3D、どうだった？どうだった？
How was Watame's 3D song? How was it?
思ったよりだいぶ可愛いねってあったの。
There were comments saying 'It's way cuter than I expected'.
思った、どんなこと思ってたんだ。
I wondered, what were you thinking?
ありがとう！でも見に来てくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you! But thank you for coming to watch!
今3位だったよ！トレンド3位だったよ！まだまだ、まだまだ足りないぜ。
We were 3rd place just now! 3rd on trending! It's still not enough.
やっぱナンバーワンがいいよな。
Number one is best, after all.
で、せっかく3Dになったんで、あの、ちょっと、全身とか見てもらいたいなって思うんだけど、
And since we've become 3D, I want you to see my whole body and everything,
じゃあまず、あの、背面、これ、背中とか見たくないですか？
so first, um, the back. Don't you want to see my back and stuff?
背中とか、見せちゃおうかな。
Should I show you my back?
あ、これ、あ、見せちゃおうかな。
Ah, should I show you?
実はあんまり知られてないんだけど、これ、後ろハーフアップになってて、
Actually, not many people know this, but it's half-up in the back,
実は結んでるんですよね、髪の毛。これチョロ毛が、実は、あるんですよね。
and my hair is actually tied. There are these little tufts of hair.
あと、しっぽがあるんですけど、
And I have a tail, but...
これ、見せても大丈夫なのかな？
...is it okay to show this?
あ、ちょっとマントが、
Ah, my cape...
あ、ちょっと見えたかな。
Ah, could you see it a bit?
別のものがみえちゃう。
I'm showing something else.
こっちからも。ここはちょっとスクショ撮ってもらった。
From this side too. I had you take a screenshot here.
難しいって。しっぽがよ、あ、来た来た。
It's hard... The tail is—ah, here it comes.
どう？
How's that?
あー、見えてしまうまで！
Ah—until it shows!
あと、これ、耳がね、実は羊の耳なんですよね。みんな、意外と知らない人が多いんだけど、これ、羊の耳。
And also, these ears are actually sheep's ears. Many people are surprisingly unaware of this, but these are sheep ears.
結構、あの、ファンアートとか描いて下さる方は気にしてくれていたみたいなんですけど、こんな感じになっています。
Quite a few people who draw fan art seemed to pay attention to it, but this is how it looks.
で、ピンクのがね、リボンになってるんですよね、実は。
And the pink one is actually a ribbon.
ちょっと覚えて帰ってもらって、お願いします。
Please remember this on your way home, I'm asking you.
あと、やっぱりみんな、あの、待機枠のコメントでもあったんだけど、
Also, after all, there were comments in the waiting room too,
脇気になります？
are you curious about my armpits?
脇これ、あ、見たくたりします？あ、脇とか見たりしますよ。
Armpits... do you want to see them? Ah, you do look at armpits.
見せちゃおうかな、本舗、あ、初公開ではないけど、
Should I show you? Well, it's not the first time, but...
こんな、あ、ちょっとあんまり、あ、そんな、あ、よら、
Like this—ah, don't—ah, if you get too close,
寄られると、ちょっと恥ずかしいと、ちょ、ちょ、あ、あ、あ、そんな寄る？
if you get that close, it's a bit embarrassing—wait, why are you getting that close?
そんな寄ります？これスクショさ、と、取られちゃうよ、一緒残っちゃうよこれ。
Are you really getting that close? You'll take a screenshot, it'll stay together with me.
歯もあるっていうね。歯も生えてんだ。
And I have teeth too. Teeth have grown in.
あ、ちゃんと歯も、あ、生えてんだ。あ。
Ah, teeth have grown in properly too. Ah.
あ、虫歯じゃないかな、大丈夫かな？恥ずかしいな。
Ah, are they not cavities? Will it be fine? How embarrassing.
あと、やっぱり一番気になるのって、
And also, after all, the thing everyone is most curious about...
これ、これ、揺れるかどうか。
...is whether this bounces or not.
え？脇で10万人達成したってコメントがいっぱい。
Eh? There are so many comments saying 'You reached 100k with your armpits'.
まだ、まだあるから。これ、行くで。
There's still more. Here we go.
あ、あ、これジャンプしてるだけですからね。あ、これジャンプしてるだけなんでね。
Ah, I'm just jumping, you know. I'm just jumping.
まあ、そんな深い意味はないけどね。
Well, it doesn't have any deep meaning.
ちょっと、なんかジャンプしたくなっちゃってさ。
I just suddenly felt like jumping.
ジャンプしたくなっちゃってさ、なんてね。画面も揺らしてもらって。
I felt like jumping, you know. I even had the screen shake.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ナーフはされませんでしたよ。
It didn't get nerfed, you know.
やったぜ！みんな見たかったでしょ。
Yay! Everyone wanted to see this, right?
実は、この後もいっぱい、ちょっと歌ったり、あとコーナーとかもあったりするので、
Actually, after this, I have a bunch of things like singing and corners coming up,
ぜひ最後まで、最後まで見てやってください。お願いします。
so please make sure to watch until the very end! Please.
あの、いろんな顔ができるんですよ、わたま。
Um, Watame can make all sorts of faces, you know.
ちょっと、アップにしてもらって、ガチ恋距離に。
So I'd like you to zoom in to a super close-up.
ガチ恋を増や、増や、あ、あ、急に言われるとちょっと、ちょっと恥ずかしい。
To increase... Ah, being told that so suddenly is a bit embarrassing.
やめろ！あんまり移すんじゃないな。
Stop it! Don't show it so much!
移せてったけど、あんまり移すんじゃないな。ほら。
Well, you managed to show it, but don't show it too much. Look.
なんだ、栗のような、口のような栗し上がった。
What's that? It puffed up like a chestnut, like a mouth.
口のような栗し上がってよ、本当にさ。
It really puffed up like a chestnut, you know.
これ、まんま、あ、どや、どや？どや？これ、わためのどや顔です。どや、どや。
Look at that smug face. Smug, smug. This is Watame's smug face.
お、これはガチ恋、いや、が、ガチ恋増えたね！ありがたい。ありがたいぜ。
Oh, super devoted fans increased! How grateful. I'm so grateful.
是非ね、あのメンバーシップとか入って貰ってね。ありがたい。見てくれてありがとう。やっぱ恥ずかしいや。
Please join the membership and stuff. Thanks for watching. It's still embarrassing.
でも、あ、ちょっと最初飛ばしすぎて、飛ばしすぎてよ、朝ここせいぼんが切れてきたかも知れん。
But, um, I went too fast at the beginning, so maybe Asakoko Seibun is running out.
ああ、朝ここ切れてきた。あ、なんかお腹も見たくなってきた。どうしよう？
Ah, Asakoko is wearing off. Oh, I'm starting to get hungry, too. What should I do?
あ、こんなところに朝ここ商品が？
Oh, what's this Asakoko product doing here?
あ、これは、シャブルタイプの朝ここですね。
Oh, this is the suckable type of Asakoko.
あの、桐生ここという同期がね、朝6時からやってるニュース番組なんですけど、朝ここ、そこで、あの、CMとかもね、担当させてもらってる朝ここ商品。これでもいろんな種類があって。
My colleague Kiryu Coco does a morning news show called Asakoko, and I handle commercials for it.
ほら、ちょっと今はシャブルタイプじゃ、あ、これ、これはめるタイプですね。
Look, now this isn't the suckable type... Ah, this is the fitting type.
これ、はめ、あ、これは塗るタイプ！大丈夫なのか映して？塗るタイプですね。ほかは？
This is... Ah, this is the apply type! Is it okay to show this? It's the apply type.
あ、これスータ、スータタイプの向きがなんか逆さまになってるんだけど。こっかな？
Oh, this is the suuta type, but the orientation is upside down.
あ、これはお風呂、お風呂の椅子から、お風呂の、座るタイプの朝ここですね。ペラペラで草。
Oh, this is the sit-on-the-chair-in-the-bath type of Asakoko. So thin it's hilarious.
でもやっぱり決めるには、あれかなあ？
But when it comes down to it, I wonder if it's...
あれしか、あ、これこれこれ！これこれこれ！
Only that one... Ah, this, this, this! This, this, this!
あ、今ね、多分誰も見てないと思うんで、みんな見てないよな？
Ah, right now, I don't think anyone is watching, so everyone isn't looking, right?
目ちょっと瞑ってて貰って、みんなちょっと、見ないで貰って。
Please close your eyes for a moment, everyone don't look.
あ、回線止まる！今回線止まってる！
Ah, connection stopping! The connection just stopped!
よっしゃ、行くで！あ、あ、ブシュッ！朝ここ効いてきたー！
Alright, let's go! Ah, pfft! Asakoko is kicking in!
ああ、あ、あ、朝ここが、何？ひびいたから、これが朝ここ中毒者ですよ、皆さん。
Ah, Asakoko hit me so hard... this is what an Asakoko addict looks like, everyone.
こんだけ決めれば、体操できそうだ！よし、
If I take this much, I can definitely do some exercise! Alright,
角巻体操、やっちゃうで！イェイ！
Tsunomaki Taisou, let's do it! Yay!
角巻体操始まるよ！
Tsunomaki Taisou is starting!
お？なんか今日は、お題がいっぱいあるみたいで、なんかわためもいっぱい出てきた！決まってんね！
Oh? Today there seem to be lots of topics, and lots of Watames appeared too! Nailed it!
お？なんだ？お？水を飲みに行くときに見せかけて、かっこいいポーズをしたあと、先輩のポーズをとる。
Oh? Pretending to go get a drink of water, doing a cool pose, and then doing a senpai pose.
任しときよ。
Leave it to me.
何の先輩ポーズ？じゃ簡単じゃん、行くぜ！
What kind of senpai pose? That's easy, let's go!
水を、飲みませんと。3Dなったやりたいポーズがあって。
I must drink water. There's a pose I wanted to do once in 3D.
行くぜ先輩のポーズ。あ、全身で、見といてよ。行くぜ。変身！ダギー！ダギダギダギダギダギー！
Let's go with the senpai pose. Watch my whole body. Here we go. Transformation! Daggy!
オレ！3段！はいかっこいい。スクショ撮ってもいいですよ。はいかっこいい。
Ore! 3rd tier! Yeah, cool. You can take screenshots. Yeah, cool.
次！感謝の正拳突き！一万回！
Next! Grateful straight punches! Ten thousand times!
一万回
Ten thousand times!
こんなに…
So much...
まあやるか。
Well, shall we do it?
まあ制限付きと言えばね、これっすよ。
Well, speaking of conditions, this is it.
これ。
This.
巻きズノンっすよ。
It's Maki-Zunon.
いくで？
Here we go?
1、2、ほんとにみんな、ありがとうございます！
1, 2, truly everyone, thank you so much!
いや、感謝してんで、
No, I'm really grateful,
5、6、7、8、写してよ！
5, 6, 7, 8, show it!
9、10、これ、一生これをみんな見ることになるんだけど大丈夫ですか？
9, 10, everyone's going to be looking at this forever, are you okay with that?
もうそろそろ、1万回やったという手でいいですかね？
Is it about time we pretend we've done it 10,000 times?
ちょ、のたうち回るわ。ちょ、のたうち回るしたおか。
Hold on, I'm gonna writhe in agony. Writhe in agony, Shitaoka.
次ゲー回そう。
Let's spin the game again.
はい。
Yes.
3回回ってガチ恋セリフ。
3 spins for a serious love dialogue.
またこれガチ恋増えちゃうけど、いくで？
This'll increase the serious love fans again though, here we go?
1、2、3、
1, 2, 3,
愛してんで！
I love you!
恥ずかしんだ。
How embarrassing.
次！次々！
Next! Next one!
荒ぶる羊のポーズ。
The wild sheep pose.
これ分かる？
Do you get this?
分かる人いますか？
Is anyone here who gets it?
いくで？ヤンダ！
Here we go? Yanda!
愛してる。
I love you.
高跳びーん！
High jump!
やばい、バランス感覚が…
Oh no, my sense of balance...
荒ぶってんな、これは、これは荒ぶってますね。
It's going wild, this is, this is definitely going wild.
次だ！
Next one!
次いくで。
Let's go to the next.
グリコじゃないよ。
It's not Glico!
グリコじゃねえよ。
It's not Glico.
荒ぶる高跳びのポーズだろ。
It's the wild high jump pose.
コメント見えてんだもん。
I can see the chat, you know.
腕を回して足も回してくるくるくるくる回転。
Rotate your arms, rotate your legs, spin round and round.
これ、あの運営さんが考えたネタですからね。
This is material the management thought of, after all.
こういうことだ、こういうことなのかな。
Is this what it is, is this what it means?
側転もできないのに、なんだ、何をやらされているんだ。
Even though I can't do a cartwheel, what am I being made to do?
次いこっ。次いくで。
Let's move on. Let's go to the next.
ガニ股のポーズ。あ、このガニ股のポーズはこれもやりたいのがあって。
Bow-legged pose. Ah, this bow-legged pose, there's something else I wanted to do.
いくで、ちょっと何のネタか分かるかな？いくよ。
Here we go, I wonder if you know what reference this is? Here we go.
パーン！
Bam!
変身！
Transformation!
ダキダキダキダキダキダキダキ。
Daki daki daki daki daki daki daki.
俺の強さに、お前が泣いた。
You cried at my strength.
ごきげん。
Good day.
これは会長にも言われてて、あのガニ股やるよなって。
The chairman told me too, that I'd be doing that bow-legged stance.
こんな感じでどう？スクショ撮ってもらって合成してもらって。
How is this? Take a screenshot and composite it.
かなたとね、会長もやってましたからね。
Kanata and, well, the chairman did it too.
でもちょっと足が補正もんで、結構きついな。
But since my legs are corrected, it's pretty tough.
で、寿司三昧じゃないよ。寿司三昧。寿司三昧じゃねえよ。
And, it's not Sushi Zanmai. Sushi Zanmai. It's not Sushi Zanmai.
裏たろすもできるよ。こうやって、こうやって変身すんだ。変身。
Urataros can do it too. Like this, you transform like this. Transformation.
また目に貫かれてみる？
Wanna get pierced through the eyes again?
次ありますか？
Is there a next one?
あ、もうなくなった。ネタいいで、ハイエーよ。
Ah, they're gone already. That's enough material, high-air.
ネタ切れハイエーで。ということで、
Material shortage high-air. So, anyways,
コメントからやってほしいポーズを募集しようとの事なんですけど、
we're calling for pose requests from the comments, but...
なんか、ありますか？なんか、ありますか？
Is there anything? Is there anything?
反復横跳びする？
Should I do side-to-side jumps?
なんかある。じょじょ立ち。
There's something. Jojo pose.
こんな感じ？あ、いいね。決ま、決まってるね。
Like this? Ah, nice. It's nailed, it's nailed.
ブレイクダンス。できない、こ、こんなんだ。
Breakdance. I can't, s-, something like this.
こんなんだろ？怒られちゃう。ブレイクダンスしてる人に怒られちゃうよ。怒られちゃうよ。
Something like this? I'll get yelled at by people who actually breakdance. I'll get yelled at.
寿司三昧。好きだな。寿司三昧。寿司三昧。
Sushi Zanmai. I love it. Sushi Zanmai. Sushi Zanmai.
マリン船長ここしか。ほいしょマリンです。
Captain Marine is the only one here. Heave-ho, it's Marine.
どんまなだけな、こんな、こんな感じだな。なんだろ、なんだろ。
How is it, something like this. What is it, what is it.
ほいしょマリンです。あってる？
Heave-ho, it's Marine. Is this right?
ボダリじゃない。ボダリじゃないよ。みんな失礼だな。
It's not Bodari. It's not Bodari. You guys are so rude.
現場猫のポーズどんだけ。
Genba Neko pose, how much is there.
よし。こんなんだっけな。よし。
Alright. Was it like this? Alright.
なんてポーズをやらされてんだ。よし。
What kind of poses am I being made to do. Alright.
命のポーズ
Pose of life!
命
Life!
あ、上手いのでわ？
Ah, is this good?
こっちかな？合ってるかな？
Is it this way? Is this right?
はい、逆か？
Wait, backwards?
こっちもやとこーか。
Let's do this side too.
あ、上手いのでわ？
Ah, is this good?
うまいのでわ？
Is this good?
よし、よし、よし
Alright, alright, alright.
ラスト1回！なんかありますか？
Last round! Anything else?
ラスト1回！
Last round!
え？
Eh?
だっちゅーの？
Datchuuno?
だっちゅーの
Datchuuno.
スクショタイムですよ！
It's screenshot time!
あ、その下からなめますように。
Ah, licking from below.
あー！あ、頭部まで！アホ毛まで！ありがとうございます！
Ah—! Ah, up to the head! Up to the ahoge! Thank you very much!
よし。
Alright.
じゃあ、体操があったらあれあるよね、みんなあれもやりたいと思うんだ。じゃあ、
Well, if there's calisthenics, there's that, right? Everyone wants to do that too. So,
3D角巻じゃんけん
3D Tsunomaki Janken!
やるで！じゃんけんの準備して、行くで！スタート！
Let's do it! Get ready for Janken, let's go! Start!
つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
つのまき つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
じゃんけんぽーん！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon!
パー！
Paper!
勝った？
Won?
負けた？あ、負けてる人多いんじゃないのこれ？
Lost? Ah, aren't there many who lost here?
じゃあ、負けた人のためにもう1回やってもいいかな？
Well, is it okay to do it one more time for those who lost?
あ、見に来てくれてありがとう！
Ah, thanks for coming to see!
もう1回やってもいい？行くで？
Can we do it one more time? Here we go?
もう1回！つのまきじゃんけん！
One more time! Tsunomaki Janken!
スタート！
Start!
つのまき つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
じゃんけんぽーん！チョキ！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon! Scissors!
チョキ！みこ先輩のためのワンモアカット！
Scissors! One more cut for Miko-senpai!
パー、パー、チョキ、グー！また負けた！
Pa, Pa, Choki, Gu! Lost again!
パーの人多いんじゃないの？ねえ、パーの人多いんじゃないの？
Aren't there a lot of Pa people? Hey, aren't there?
じゃあ、これもう1回やってもいいかな？あの、素材をせっかくね、作っていただいたので、
Well, is it okay if we do this one more time? Since they specially made the assets for us,
二連敗してる人のために！スタート！つのまきじゃんけん！スタート！
For those who lost twice! Start! Tsunomaki Janken! Start!
つのまき つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
じゃんけんぽーん！グー！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon! Rock!
まさか3連敗した人はいないよな？
Surely nobody lost 3 times in a row, right?
全部使ったで！グー、パー、チョキ、グーだったかな、全部使ったで！
Used 'em all! Gu, Pa, Choki, Gu, right? Used 'em all!
さすがに負けたやつおらんやろ、3連敗はおらんやろ！
Surely nobody lost, nobody lost 3 times in a row!
おるな？負けてる人、おるで？
There are? There are people who lost?
しょうがない、泣きの1回やるで！泣きの1回、ラスト、ラストね！ホンマにラストよ！
Can't be helped, I'll do one crying round! One crying round, last, last! Truly the last!
スタート！
Start!
つのまきじゃんけん！スタート！
Tsunomaki Janken! Start!
つのまき つのまき つのまき つのまき
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki...
じゃんけんぽーん！パー！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon! Paper!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
カニカニカニカニ…ウニカニカニカニ…
Kani, kani, kani... Uni, kani, kani...
ニーーー！
Niiii...!
かに かに かに かに かに かに
Crab, crab, crab, crab, crab, crab...
にー！
Ni!
ん？
Hm?
なな？
Nana?
ん？
Hm?
はーい！
Yay!
かに かに かに かに かに かに
Crab, crab, crab, crab, crab, crab...
にー！
Ni!
ん？
Hm?
なな？
Nana?
ん？
Hm?
はーい！
Yay!
かに かに かに かに かに かに
Crab, crab, crab, crab, crab, crab...
にー！
Ni!
四季の羊えっとね
Four thousand sheep, let's see...
クソ雑魚ケダマなんてめずらし
Such rare little weakling hairballs...
誰が負けるかそんなディスね
Who would lose to a dis like that?
リスン トゥー ミー いつも聞いてみ
Listen to me, always listen to me
歌う時は君のため うつむいてちゃダメダメよ
I'm singing for you, don't look down!
元気でますよ お試しあれ
You'll feel better, give it a try
ドジな羊でごめんねえ
Sorry for being a clumsy sheep
回線落ちた配線たちから学んだ敗戦
Defeat learned from dropped-connection wiring...
なんせここは ホロライブ
After all, this is Hololive!
あったけェ 仲間達がいりゅ 間違うことはあったって
Warm comrades are here, making mistakes happens
下向かず進むよ
Don't look down, keep moving forward!
順風満帆なの知ってんだぜ
I know it's plain sailing,
順風歩行は いずこへ せいやっ
But where is smooth walking? Seiya!
ここからとわの彼方へ とまるな ほらほら 川が叫べ お前ら
From here to eternity, don't stop, look, the river shouts, you guys!
いつかに捨てた夢があるなら 私目とひろやあつめよ
If you have an abandoned dream, gather my eyes and spread them!
ここからとわの彼方へ とまるな ほらほら 川が叫べ お前ら
From here to eternity, don't stop, look, the river shouts, you guys!
いつかに捨てた夢があるなら 私目とひろやあつめよ
If you have an abandoned dream, gather my eyes and spread them!
サビに四季生全員の名前が入っている わためラップでしたー！
That was the Watame rap with all 4th generation members' names!
緊張するなー
I was so nervous haha!
そして これ サングラス見ててよ
And look at these sunglasses.
角巻わための
Tsunomaki Watame's...
サングラスだーーん！ どう？
sunglasses! Tada! How are they?
ナイトフィーバーっぽい でしょ？
Looks like Night Fever, right?
あ これっ
Ah, this...
これ実は あの 宝鐘マリンさんのネタをリスペクトして作ってもらいましたー
Actually, I had these made out of respect for Houshou Marine's bit!
宝鐘マリンの っていうネタがあるんだけど、角巻わためのサングラスどう？
She has this 'Houshou Marine's...' bit, so how are Tsunomaki Watame's sunglasses?
いやこのサングラス、多分この後もう出てこないので、今のうちにスクショ撮って
These sunglasses probably won't appear anymore after this, so take a screenshot right now!
あ、これ、あ、ちょうど指が、あ、あ、シャープ！角巻わため3Dこのハッシュタグをつけて、ぜひたくさんツイートしてください！
Ah, right here, fingers are, ah, sharp! Tsunomaki Watame 3D, please tweet a lot with this hashtag!
たくさんの人に見てもらいましょうぜ！みんなの力でよ！だだだだーん！
Let's have lots of people see it! With everyone's power! Tada-da-da-daan!
サングラスもよ、覚えたんで、今のうちにスクショいっぱいいっといてね。
I memorized the sunglasses too, so take plenty of screenshots right now.
お？お？お、いいな。お、お、オッケー。オッケー。
Oh? Oh? Oh, nice. Oh, oh, okay. Okay.
では 次の曲なんですけど、みんな越えられるのか？あまぎ、越えられるかーー？
Now, for the next song... can everyone overcome it? Amagi, can you overcome it?!
あー でも このままだと越えられないかもしれない。あ、この後ゴロにまた、あそこかーー！
Ah... but at this rate, we might not be able to overcome it. Ah, after this, Goro again... ah, right there!
あなごごごー
Ah, anagogogo...
ちょっと、あ、決めさせてもらって。
Wait, uh, let me decide.
あ、そうじゃ、待てよ。
Ah, that's right, wait.
これを決めさせてもらって、あそこは扱いが難しいぜ。
Let me decide on this one, that place is tricky to handle.
ぶしゅっ。あー。
*Psh*. Ah...
聞いた、聞いたー。
I heard it, I heard it!
あなごごご聞いてきたー。
Anagogogo, I heard it!
これで越えられるかも。
Maybe I can overcome it with this.
では聴いてください、「甘ギ声」。
Now, please listen to "Sweet Voice".
まさかの、まさかの3Dで
In a 3D stream, of all things,
まさかの3Dで 甘ギ声を
choosing a sweet voice—
チョイスした角巻わためです
I'm Tsunomaki Watame!
これはコメント欄 みんな あと遊ぶというか 盛り上がってください
Everyone in the chat, let's play, or rather, get hyped!
越えられるのか3回も
Can I really overcome it three times?
ああ、そうなんだ 角巻わためで甘ギ声
Ah, is that so? Tsunomaki Watame's sweet voice...
隠しきれない 移り気が
My undeniable fickleness
いつしかあなたに 染みついた
eventually rubbed off on you.
誰かに取られる くらいなら
Rather than having you taken by someone else,
あなたを殺して いいですか
is it okay if I kill you?
眠たれて 隠れ宿
Sleeping in a hidden inn,
綴らうより 常連の滝 舞い上がり
weaving stories, soaring up the waterfall of regulars,
揺れ落ちる 刃の向こうに あなた
you are beyond the swaying, falling blade.
山が燃える 何があっても もういいの
The mountain burns. No matter what happens, it's fine now.
クラクラ燃える日をくぐり あなたと
Passing through the dizzyingly burning days,
超えたい
I want to surpass it with you.
甘ギ声
Sweet voice...
超えたー 超えたー
I surpassed it! I surpassed it!
お、2番は行けんのか？
Oh, can I do the second verse?
口を開けば 別れると
If we open our mouths, we'll break up—
刺さったままの 割れガラス
shattered glass still stuck in us.
二人でいたって 寒いけど
Even being together is cold,
嘘でも抱かれりゃ 温かい
but being held, even in a lie, is warm.
わさび沢 隠れ道
Wasabi swamp, hidden path,
さよしぐれ 観音橋 恨んでも
Kannon bridge in evening drizzle, no matter how much I resent it,
恨んでも 体裏腹 あなた
no matter how much my body contradicts my mind, you—
山が燃える 戻れなくても もういいの
The mountain burns. Even if we can't go back, it's fine now.
クラクラ燃える血をはって あなたと
Crawling through the dizzyingly burning blood,
超えたい
I want to surpass it with you.
甘ギ声 超えたー 超えたー
Sweet voice! I surpassed it! I surpassed it!
走り水 迷い恋
Running water, stray love,
風の群れ 甘い追憶 恨んでも
flock of winds, sweet memories, no matter how much I resent them,
恨んでも 体裏腹 あなた
no matter how much my body contradicts my mind, you—
山が燃える 戻れなくても もういいの
The mountain burns. Even if we can't go back, it's fine now.
クラクラ燃える血をはって あなたと
Crawling through the dizzyingly burning blood,
超えたい
I want to surpass it with you.
甘ギ声
Sweet voice...
これだ！みんなのおかげで越えれたよ。ありがとう！
That's it! Thanks to everyone, I was able to make it through. Thank you!
やあ！
Yay!
みんなのおかげで甘口越えれたよ、ありがとう！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to get through the sweet level! Thank you!
３回も、３回も越えたで、やった！
Three times, I got through it three times, yay!
万歳！万歳！あ、脇が見える、万歳！やったー！
Banzai! Banzai! Ah, my armpits are showing, banzai! Yay!
うた、大丈夫だったかな？どうだったかな？
Was my singing okay? How was it?
あ、うまかった？素晴らしかった？やったー！ありがとう！
Ah, was it good? Was it wonderful? Yay! Thank you!
角巻わため３D化記念グッズ
Tsunomaki Watame 3D Commemorative Goods
アクリルスタンド＆コースターセットがセットで販売開始なんですが、
Acrylic Stand & Coaster Set will go on sale as a set!
このあと21時より販売開始になりますで、
Sales will start at 9:00 PM tonight,
概要欄の方に販売ページが書いてあるので、よかったら9時になったらポチッとしてね？
and the purchase link is in the description box, so please check it out at 9:00!
数量限定販売なんですけど、大量に作ってってお願いしてあるので、
It's a limited quantity sale, but I asked them to make a huge amount,
そんな急がなくても大丈夫だと思うので、ぜひ記念にいかがでしょうか？
so you don't have to rush too much. How about getting it as a memento?
あと特典付きのお誕生日ボイスも明日のお昼12時までなので気をつけてね！
Also, the birthday voice with bonus items is available until 12:00 PM tomorrow!
そしてこのあと9時15分に初めてのオリジナル楽曲「愛味ショコラッテ」のプレミア公開します！
And right after this broadcast at 9:15 PM, my first original song "Aimai Chocolate" premieres!
ああ、あまやっちゃった
Ah, I messed up again...
隠してたわけじゃないの
It's not like I was hiding it.
きっとただ言ってないだけ
I just didn't mention it.
だって、恥ずかしいんだもん
Because it's too embarrassing!
意外と寂しんぼ
I get surprisingly lonely,
意外と甘えんぼ
surprisingly spoiled,
意外と慌てんぼ
surprisingly in a rush,
意外と照れ屋
and a bit shy.
丸い飛行機雲
Like a round contrail,
飛び出したカップケーキ
a cupcake that popped out,
3回目コンディショナー
conditioning for the third time,
余るパズルピース
or an extra puzzle piece.
ふわふわ浮かぶ夢見心地
Floating lightly, feeling like a dream,
ひとつひとつ数えておやすみなさい
counting one by one, good night.
密かに芽生えたこのキモチ
This feeling that secretly sprouted,
まっすぐ見つめないで
don't stare straight at me.
「なんだったっけ…///」
"What was it again...?"
言葉にしちゃうときっとそうじゃない
Putting it into words isn't right either,
照れいちゃうだけおちらんないしゅじゃない
I just get too shy and tongue-tied.
本当の本当は隠したいんじゃないのかなー
The truth is, I wonder if I want to hide it—
そうじゃないのにさぁ
even though that's not true at all.
曖昧なんていうない
Don't call it vague!
このキモチは間違いじゃない
This feeling is not a mistake.
指切りげんまん
Pinky swear,
かなりドジっ子で
I'm quite clumsy
優柔不断でも
and indecisive at times,
絶対に毎日
but you'll still come and see me
愛いに来てくれるよね？
every single day, right?
本来怯病で
I'm naturally timid,
案外泣き虫
and surprisingly a crybaby,
全然変わらず
but completely unchanged,
元来君ばかり！
always thinking only of you!
当たり前のようにきゅんしちゃう
I fall for you as if it's the most natural thing,
君がいないとがっかりしちゃう
without you I feel so let down.
本当の本当にしょぼんしちゃうわ会いたくなっちゃうな
It really makes me so sad, I just want to see you.
後悔ばっかりしちゃう
I always end up regretting,
この心も勇気出しちゃえ
but this time I'll gather my courage,
この指とまれ
hop onto this finger!
弱いところ気づかれたり
Having my weaknesses noticed,
寂しさごと包まれたり
being wrapped up in my loneliness,
いつでも笑い合ったり
always laughing together,
たまにはむっと喧嘩をしたり
and sometimes getting into little fights—
ずーっとずーっとそばにいてほしい
I want you to stay by my side forever and ever.
…約束だぞ。
...It's a promise.
「いっちまった///」
"I actually said it...!"
もしかしたら運命かも
Maybe this is fate,
赤い糸が見えちゃうかも
maybe the red thread is visible.
本当の本当は
The absolute truth is...
あーあ またやっちゃった
Ah... I messed up again.
隠してたわけじゃないの きっとただ言ってないだけで
It's not like I was hiding it, I just didn't say it.
照れちゃうじゃん ちゃらけちゃうじゃん
It's too embarrassing, right? Acting all playful, right?
本当の本当は隠したいんじゃないの
The truth is, it's not that I want to hide it.
もっとじゃないのに な
Even though I want more, you know.
曖昧なんじゃない
It's not vague at all.
この気持ちは間違いじゃない
This feeling can't be wrong.
指切りげんま
Pinky swear.
かなりドジっ子で 優柔不断でも
I'm a bit clumsy and indecisive,
紆余曲折でも
Through all the twists and turns,
絶対に毎日
You'll definitely come see me
会いに来てくれるよね
Every single day, right?
本当臆病で
I'm actually timid,
案外泣き虫
And quite a crybaby,
全然変わらずに 元気君ばかり
Yet my eyes are still fixed only on you!
当たり前のよう
Like it's the most natural thing,
に ギュッてしちゃう 君がいないと
I hold you tight. Without you here,
がっかりしちゃう 本当の本当に
I get so disappointed, and really, really
ションボリしちゃうわ
I feel so down,
会いたくなっちゃうの
I end up wanting to see you.
後悔ばっかりしちゃう この心も
I always have regrets, but with this heart
勇気出しちゃえ
I'll muster up my courage!
指切りげんま
Pinky swear.
みんなのおかげで オリジナル曲が作れました
Thanks to everyone, I was able to make an original song!
本当にありがとうございます
Thank you truly so much.
みんなのことを思って この歌詞をお願いして作ってもらいました
I asked them to write these lyrics thinking of everyone.
これからは 自分でも作ったりしていけるように頑張っていく満
From now on, I'll work hard to be able to write my own songs too!
弱いところ気付かれたり
When my weak sides are noticed,
寂しさごときゅっとつめられたり
Or when loneliness fills me up,
いつまでも笑い合ったり たまにはむっと喧嘩をしたり
Laughing together forever, or sometimes getting into a huffy fight,
ずーっとずーっとそばにいてほしい
I want you by my side forever and ever.
「言っちゃった…///」
"I said it...///"
もしかしたら運命かも 赤い糸が見えちゃうかも
Maybe it's destiny, maybe I can see the red thread.
本当の本当にバレてるのかも 目合わせられないかも
Maybe the truth is completely exposed, maybe I can't meet your eyes.
曖昧なんぜない たくさんわたしを見せて
It's not vague at all, look at me lots!
指切った！
Pinky sworn!
ありがとう
Thank you!
泣きそうに 泣きそうになっちゃったよ
I'm gonna cry, I'm gonna cry!
今
Just now,
頭に脳に直接 言葉が入ってきたんだけど
Words came straight into my brain,
日本 世界
Japan, the world,
ともに Twitterトレンドが
Together, my Twitter trend rank was...
1位？ ナンバーワン？ 2位？ なんたととか？
1st place? Number one? 2nd? Something like that?
やったーー！！
Yay!!
本当に みんなのおかげです ありがとうございます
Truly, this is thanks to everyone. Thank you so much!
いや、今日が来るまで ね みんな見に来てくれるかな とか
I mean, until today, I wondered if everyone would come see me,
ちゃんと こう みんな見てる前で 歌えるかな とか
And if I'd be able to sing properly in front of everyone watching,
本当は ちょっとね不安な気持ちもあったんだけど
And honestly, I had some anxious feelings too,
運営さんもいっぱい頑張ってくれて こうやってみんな ね 時間をとって
But management worked so hard, and everyone took the time,
貴重な時間をとって見に来てくれて あとは先輩とか同期もね 宣伝してくれたりして
Taking precious time to come see me, and my seniors and peers helped promote it too.
本当にみんな ありがとう！ ありがとう！
Truly everyone, thank you! Thank you!
ふみママもけっぴパパも本当にありがとうございます
Fumi-mama and Keppi-papa, thank you so much too.
いつもお世話になって
Always taking care of me.
あと あのせっかくなので このナイトフィーバーの会場とかって 見れるんかな？
Also, since we're at it, can we see this Night Fever venue and stuff?
無茶ぶりしてるけど
I'm making unreasonable requests though!
これ実はすごくね あの ナイトフィーバーしたいって言ったら このステージを作ってくださったんですよ
Actually, when I said I wanted to do 'Night Fever', they built this stage for me!
ちょっと かすんで 自分 画面が見えないんだけど も 目がかすんで あ、見えた！
It's a bit blurry and I can't see the screen... my eyes are blurry—ah, I can see it!
ミーナ！ これ、実は
Mina! This is actually...
周りにいっぱいい、羊が、わためいとが、おるんですよ、これ。
Look at all these sheep around, Watameitos are everywhere, you know.
しかも角のかわりにサイリウムが刺さってる、ちょっとね、ちょっと狂気的な（笑）
And instead of horns, they have Cyalume glow sticks stuck in their heads... a bit unhinged, haha!
しかも2階席とかもあって、
And there are even second-tier seats,
すごいよ！後ろのDJもね、羊さんが、わためいとが頑張ってDJやってくれて。
it's amazing! And the DJ in the back, a sheep, a Watameito, worked hard to be the DJ for me.
そう、2階席もね、いるんですよ。どー？
Yeah, there are people in the second tier too. How is it?
これ360度になっていて、あ、あげはっぽい、あ（笑）
It's 360 degrees, oh, looks like a swallowtail, ahaha.
そういう、なんだろうな、ディスコクラブ的なところと、あとこのお立ち台とかが、あ、かわいいね！頑張って！かわいいね、頭振ってね。
Like a disco club sort of place, and these pedestals... ah, so cute! Do your best! So cute, shaking your head.
あ、ヘッドバンもやりたいね、あ、ミラーボールも、あ、すごくないですかこれ？細かくない？
Ah, I want to headbang too, oh, the mirror ball too, ah, isn't this amazing? Isn't it detailed?
光が、黄色とか、そう、ピンクとか、星型とか、めちゃくちゃ細かく作ってくれてるんですよ。
The lights, yellow and, yeah, pink and star shapes, they made it so incredibly detailed.
すごいね！これがホロライブやで！
It's amazing! This is Hololive!
すごいよね（笑）ヘッドバンやろっか。
Isn't it amazing? Haha. Let's do some headbanging.
あの後ろの羊とともに。
Together with the sheep in the back.
あ、ガンギマ、ガンギマリ顔をしようかな、ちょっと。海外肉も観に来てくれてありがとう！
Ah, let's make a completely zonked, zonked-out face, just a bit. Thank you overseas meat (fans) for coming to watch too!
ガンギマリ、ヘッドバン！わあー！
Zonked out, headbang! Waaah!
うわあー！うわあー！いつもやってる。
Uwaah! Uwaah! I always do this.
うわあー！どうですか？
Uwaah! How is it?
ま、あ、は、鼻が…
Wait, ah, ha, my nose...
は、鼻の天然水がちょっと、は、鼻の天然水が、ちょっと出てしまいました、すま、鼻の天然水が、ちょっと出てしまいましたね（笑）
M-my natural nose water... m-my natural nose water leaked out a bit, sorr—my natural nose water leaked out a bit, haha.
あ、ちょっと拭かせて頂戴。
Ah, let me wipe it off a bit.
まさかの、あ、あや、あや、あや、言います。あ、ティッシュで拭かせて頂戴。
Of all things, a-aya, aya, aya, I mean. Ah, let me wipe it with a tissue.
は、鼻の天然水、拭きました！拭きました！
N-natural nose water, I wiped it! I wiped it!
ありがとうございます！（笑）
Thank you very much! Haha.
あの配信中もね、鼻の天然水が、あの結構出たりするんですけども、今日もまさかのこんなたくさんの人の前で鼻の天然水が出てしまうとは思っていませんでした、これはね、あのちょっと
Even during streams, you know, my natural nose water tends to come out quite a bit, but I never thought my natural nose water would come out in front of so many people today, this is, you know, sort of...
ちょっと、放送事故ですね（笑）
A bit of a broadcasting accident, haha.
あ、失礼！失礼いたしました！失礼いたしました！
Ah, excuse me! Excuse me! Excuse me!
ね、みんなたくさん観に来てくれて、ありがとう！ありがとう！
You know, everyone came to watch in such numbers, thank you! Thank you!
今ね、そう、ふぶく先輩とか、フータンとか、あとランちゃんも観てたよね？観ててコメント！
Right now, you know, Fubuki-senpai, Fu-tan, and also Ran-chan were watching, right? Watching and commenting!
会長もありがとう！みんなありがとう来てくれて、本当に！
Kaichou too, thank you! Thank you everyone for coming, really!
危ない、もっと泣くかと思ったで。危なかったで。
Oh no, I thought I'd cry more. That was close.
でもみんながこうやって支えてくれてるって思うと、やっぱりしっかり最後まで歌い切りたいなと思って、
But thinking about how everyone is supporting me like this, I really want to sing my heart out right until the very end,
ちょっとね、終わってから泣こうと、一度病院に行ったほうがいい？動物病院に、そこだけは行きたくないんだ。動物病院だけは嫌なんだ。
so you know, I'll cry after it ends... Should I go to the hospital once? To the animal hospital? I don't want to go there. I only hate the animal hospital.
嫌なんだ。
I hate it.
メル先輩もありがとう！メル先輩もありがとう！
Mel-senpai, thank you too! Mel-senpai, thank you too!
そして、わためいともいつもありがとう！本当にありがとう！今日初めて知ってくださった方も、ありがとうございます！
And Watameito, thank you as always! Thank you so much! And thank you to everyone who found out about me for the first time today!
是非、角巻わため、あの、覚えて帰って貰って、名前だけでも覚えて帰って貰って、覚えて帰って貰って！
Please remember Tsunomaki Watame and take that home with you, take even just my name home with you, take it home with you!
よろしくお願いします！
I look forward to working with you!
本当に今日はみんなありがとう！寂しいけど、
Truly, thank you everyone today! It's lonely, but...
実は、もうラスト1曲なんです！あっというまだね！4期生全員と、バカタレどもも、もうコールでなんと参加してくれて、いま！
Actually, it's already the last song! That was fast! All the 4th gen members and the Bakatare-domo have participated with calls right now!
イエーイ！イェイイェイイェイ！なので、みんなもサイリウム、ペンライト、タオルを振るなりコールをするなりして、一緒に盛り上がってください！
Yay! Yay yay yay! So everyone, please wave your Cyalume, penlights, towels, or do calls, and let's get hyped together!
行くで！ラスト1曲、好きで！
Let's go! Last song, "Sukide"!
お前の勇気 誇る時
When you take pride in your courage,
運命の扉は 開かれず
the doors of destiny remain unopened.
それは弱音か 永遠の闇か
Is that cowardice, or eternal darkness?
鋼の拳に 奇跡を呼ぶがよい
Summon a miracle to your steel fists!
遥かなる おお空に
Far away into the vast sky,
光の矢を 放つんだ
let loose an arrow of light!
I can fly!
You can fly!
We can fly!
もっともっと！ Kill my sail!
More and more! Kill my sail!
銀河の果てまで 熱い夢を燃やせ
Burn your passionate dreams to the galaxy's end!
Kill my soul 魂を呼び覚ませ
Kill my soul, awaken your soul!
時代が俺を導く限り 無敵さ
As long as the era guides me, I'm invincible!
手を切り裂く 巨大な剣
A gigantic sword that tears open hands,
奇跡の力 蘇る
the power of miracles revives.
愛するみんなよ 熱い胸で
Everyone I love, with a burning heart,
鋼の身びとを 危険へ
lead steel-clad people into danger!
新たな伝説を 今この手で 刻むんだ
Carve a new legend with these hands right now!
I can fly!
You can fly!
We can fly!
もっともっと！ Kill my sail!
More and more! Kill my sail!
銀河の彼方へ 物語も飛ばせ
Send the story soaring to the galaxy's edge!
I never die! Kill my soul!
なんでもいいから 立ち上がれ
Stand up no matter what!
未来が俺を導く限り 果てしない
As long as the future guides me, it's endless!
愛のせいだ これがありがとう みんな最高だありがとう
It's all love, thank you everyone, you're the best!
遥かなる おお空に
Far away into the vast sky,
光の矢を 放つんだ
let loose an arrow of light!
I can fly!
You can fly!
We can fly!
もっともっと！ Kill my sail!
More and more! Kill my sail!
足りないぞ！ I can fly!
It's not enough! I can fly!
You can fly!
We can fly!
もっともっと！ Kill my sail!
More and more! Kill my sail!
もっともっと もっともっと もっともっと 最高だありがとう！
More and more, you're the best, thank you!
手を切り裂く 巨大な剣
A gigantic sword that tears open hands,
奇跡の力 蘇る
the power of miracles revives.
愛するみんなよ 熱い胸で
Everyone I love, with a burning heart,
鋼の身びとを 危険へ
lead steel-clad people into danger!
新たな伝説を 今この手で 刻むんだ
Carve a new legend with these hands right now!
今日はその巻きわための3Dを、3Dライブにお越し下さり、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for joining today's 3D live!
これからもその巻きわため、この後にも重大発表が続く4期生、そしてホロライブ...
Stay tuned for more major announcements from Hololive!
どうも！よろしくお願いいたします！
Hello! Thank you very much!
このあとの動画も、あ、あるとか？見てね！
There's another video after this, right? Watch it!
よろしくー！
Thanks!
なのら、なのら、なのらが用意できた。
Nanora, nanora, nanora is ready.
なのら、なのら、なのらはかわいいよ。
Nanora, nanora, nanora is cute.
みんなおる？
Are you all here?
7月15日水曜日の夜の時間に、姫森ルーナのスーパーミラクルウルトラ重大発表配信があるから、
On Wednesday night, July 15th, Himemori Luna's super-miracle-ultra major announcement stream will be held,
みんなすべからく見るのだ！
so everyone absolutely must watch it!
んーーーな！
Nnnna!